Ernst Bacon Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Correspondence, 1898-1990 (Box 41-51)
  - General Correspondence (Box 43-51)
    - Peabody Institute, 1966-68, 1974-75 (Box-folder 48/25)
    - Phi Mu Alpha Sinfonia, 1939 Feb. 15 (Box-folder 48/26)
    - The Philadelphia Orchestra Association, 1938 (Box-folder 48/27)
    - The Philharmonic Symphony Society of New York, 1947 Feb. 13 (Box-folder 48/28)
    - Philosophical Library, Inc., 1986 Mar. 31 (Box-folder 48/29)
    - Pillsbury, Madison & Sutro, 1979 (Box-folder 48/30)
    - Placement Committee for German and Austrian Musicians, 1939 (Box-folder 48/31)
    - Pleasants, Henry, 1963 (Box-folder 48/32)
    - Plymouth Rock Center of Music & Drama, Inc. see: McClosky, David Blair
    - Pollak, Robert, 1937-39 (Box-folder 48/33)
    - The Post Apollo Press, 1989 (Box-folder 48/34)
    - Price, Leontine, 1989 July 6 (Box-folder 48/35)
    - Prime Minister of England see: Thatcher, Margaret
    - Princeton University Library, 1974 Feb. 14 (Box-folder 48/36)
    - "P" Miscellaneous (Box-folder 48/37)
    - "Q" Miscellaneous (Box-folder 48/38)
    - The Reader's Digest, 1965, 1977 (Box-folder 48/39)
    - Redlands Community Music Association see: Leschui, Joana
    - Reese, Gustave, 1939, 1944 (Box-folder 48/40)
    - Reis, Clarke, 1975, n.d. (Box-folder 48/41)
    - Richmond Symphony Chorus, 1967 Dec. 21 (Box-folder 48/42)
    - Robert Shaw Chorale see: Shaw, Robert
    - The Rochester Civic Music Association see: Harrison, Guy Fraser
    - Rockefellow, Martha Baird see: Aid to Music Program
    - The Rosamond Gifford Charitable Corporation, 1967 June 8 (Box-folder 48/43)
    - Ross, Hugh, 1938-44, 1950 (Box-folder 48/44)
    - Royal College of Music, 1971 Oct. 22 (Box-folder 48/45)
    - Rutgers, The State University, 1974 Mar. 28 (Box-folder 48/46)
    - The Rydal Press, 1986 (Box-folder 48/47)
    - "R" Miscellaneous (Box-folder 48/48)
    - SA Sopken Arts, Inc., 1963-64 (Box-folder 48/49)
    - Saben, Mowry, 1935-38 (Box-folder 48/50)
    - Sacramento Symphony Association, 1964 Apr. 2 (Box-folder 48/51)
    - St. Lawrence University, 1972-76 (Box-folder 49/13)
    - St. Olaf College, 1961-66 (Box-folder 49/14)
    - St. Paul's Church, 1953 Feb. 25 (Box-folder 49/15)
    - Salem College, 1945 Jan. 4 (Box-folder 48/52)
    - San Diego State College, 1960 Oct. 28 (Box-folder 48/53)
    - San Francisco Chronicle, 1965-66, 1973, 1981-89, n.d. (Box-folder 48/54)
    - The San Francisco Conservatory of Music, Inc., 1939, 1966-1974 (Box-folder 48/55)
    - The San Francisco Foundation, 1974 Nov. 11 (Box-folder 48/56)
    - San Francisco Girls Chorus, 1989 Mar. 14 (Box-folder 48/57)
    - [San Francisco, Office of the Mayor], 1985 Apr. 25 (Box-folder 48/58)
    - San Francisco Opera Association, 1964 Mar. 18 (Box-folder 48/59)
    - San Francisco Overland Limited, 1937 (Box-folder 48/60)
    - San Francisco Public Library, 1939 Apr. 11 (Box-folder 48/61)
    - San Francisco State College, 1958, 1963 (Box-folder 48/62)
    - San Francisco Symphony 1964, 1985-89 (Box-folder 48/63)
    - San Francisco Theological Seminary, 1965 May 29 (Box-folder 48/64)
    - San Jose Mercury News, 1988 Nov. 9 (Box-folder 48/65)
    - Sandburg, Carl, 1930-33 see also: Iconography series, Drawings, Caricature of Ernst Bacon (Box-folder 48/66)
    - Santa Fe Chamber Music Festival, 1976 (Box-folder 48/67)
    - Sarah Lawrence College, 1939-40 (Box-folder 48/68)
    - The Saturday Evening Post, 1939 Dec. 11 (Box-folder 48/69)
    - Saturday Review, 1958-69, n.d. (Box-folder 48/70)
    - Saunders, A. P., 1938-39, 1945 (Box-folder 48/71)
    - Schevill, Ferdinand, 192[6?], 1928, 1952, n.d. (Box-folder 48/72)
    - Schola Cantorum of New York see: Ross, Hugh
    - Seattle Symphony Orchestra, 1944 (Box-folder 48/73)
    - Shaw, Robert, 1954-57, n.d. (Box-folder 48/74)
    - Shawnee Press Inc., 1981, 1985 (Box-folder 48/75)
    - Sherman, Clay & Co., 1932 July 20 (Box-folder 48/76)
    - Siegmeister, Elie, 1955 Apr. 11 (Box-folder 48/77)
    - Sierra Club, 1964 June 10 (Box-folder 48/78)
    - Sigma Alpha Iota, 1987 Jan. 5 (Box-folder 48/79)
    - Simon & Schuster, Inc., 1950 Feb (Box-folder 48/80)
    - Sinclair, Upton, 1941 Dec 17 (Box-folder 48/81)
    - Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1950, 1971, 1989 (Box-folder 48/82)
    - Sly, Alan, 1938-1945, 1963-1965, 1971-1990, n.d., Folders: 49/1 1938-45 49/2 1963-65, 1971-78 49/3 1979-85 49/4 1986-90, n.d. (Box-folder 49/1-4)
    - Smith, Melville see: Longy School of Music
    - Smith College, 1974 Feb. 14 (Box-folder 49/5)
    - Society for the Publication of American Music, 1939 Nov. 13 (Box-folder 49/6)
    - Sokoloff, Vladimir, 1962, 1979, 1987 (Box-folder 49/7)
    - Sonneck, Oscar see: G. Schirmer, Inc.
    - Southern Connecticut State College, 1964 July 21 (Box-folder 49/8)
    - Southern Literary Messenger, 1940-48, 1950, n.d. (Box-folder 49/9)
    - The Southwestern Musician, 1948 (Box-folder 49/10)
    - Sowerby, Leo, 1933, 1964-66, n.d. (Box-folder 49/11)
    - Sponsors of San Francisco Performing Art Center, Inc., 1979 June 5 (Box-folder 49/12)
    - Stanford Democratic Committee, n.d. (Box-folder 49/16)
    - Stanford University, 1935, 1938, 1958 (Box-folder 49/17)
    - State Teachers College, 1948 (Box-folder 49/18)
    - State University of New York, 1953, 1961, 1966 (Box-folder 49/19)
    - Stock, Fredrick A., 1939-40 (Box-folder 49/20)
    - Strickland, William, 1962 Sept. 12 (Box-folder 49/21)
    - Supreme Court of California, 1986 (Box-folder 49/22)
    - Swan, Eunny, 1953, n.d. (Box-folder 49/23)
    - Swift, Page, 1978-88 (Box-folder 49/24)
    - Syracuse Savings Bank, 1948 Jan. 8 (Box-folder 49/25)
    - Syracuse Symphony Orchestra, 1973 Dec. 13 (Box-folder 49/26)
    - Syracuse University, 1943-1976, 1989 see also: Community Concert Service see also: Nowak, Lionel, Folders: 49/27 1943 Dec.-1947 Feb. 25 49/28 1947 Mar.-1949 Dec. 49/29 1950-59 49/30 1960-69 50/1 1970-76, 1989 50/2 Miscellaneous, 1949-54, n.d. 50/3 Undated (Box-folder 49/27-29, Box-folder 50/1-3)
    - Syracuse University Library see: Syracuse University
    - Syracuse University Press see: Syracuse University
    - Szell, George, 1944, 1955 (Box-folder 50/4)
    - Szigeti, Joeseph, 1944-46, n.d. (Box-folder 50/5)
    - "S" Miscellaneous (Box-folder 50/6)
    - Televents, 1986 Sept. 3 (Box-folder 50/7)
    - Thatcher, Margaret, 1989 Dec. 5 (Box-folder 50/8)
    - Theater Dance Company, 1939 (Box-folder 50/9)
    - The Theatre Guild, Inc. see: Langner, Lawrence
    - Theodore Presser Company, 1964 Aug. 31 (Box-folder 50/10)
    - The Thorne Music Fund, Inc., 1970 (Box-folder 50/11)
    - Time, 1940 Dec. 21 (Box-folder 50/12)
    - The Times Herald see: Gunn, Glen Dillard
    - Toronto Symphony Orchestra Association, 1951 Feb. 2 (Box-folder 50/13)
    - "T" Miscellaneous (Box-folder 50/14)
    - U.S.S. Marvin Shields (DE-1066), 1972-73 (Box-folder 50/15)
    - Unidentified Miscellaneous, 1915-1989, undated, Folders: 50/16 1915-39 50/17 1940-89 50/18 Undated I 50/19 Undated II (Box-folder 50/16-19)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America, 1983 Feb. 14 (Box-folder 50/20)
    - United States Department of Interior, 1937 Sept. 10 (Box-folder 50/21)
    - United States Information Agency, 1961 Feb. 20 (Box-folder 50/22)
    - United States Veterans Bureau, 1925 Apr. 1 (Box-folder 50/23)
    - Universität Graz see: Musikwissenschaftliches Institut
    - University of Arizona, 1966-67 (Box-folder 50/24)
    - University of California, 1938-86 see also: Harris, Johana (Box-folder 50/25)
    - University of Chicago, 1920, 1935-41 (Box-folder 50/26)
    - University of Colorado, 1966, 1968 (Box-folder 50/27)
    - University of Delaware, 1948 Jan. 8 (Box-folder 50/28)
    - University of Denver, 1944-51, 1966, 1975 (Box-folder 50/29)
    - University of Houston, 1989 (Box-folder 50/30)
    - The University of Idaho, 1967 Jan. 5 (Box-folder 50/31)
    - University of Illinois, 1966, 1986 (Box-folder 50/32)
    - University of Iowa, 1974 Mar. 4 (Box-folder 50/33)
    - University of Kansas, 1959 Aug. 31 (Box-folder 50/34)
    - University of Kentucky, 1948 May 22 (Box-folder 50/35)
    - University of Louisville, 1988 (Box-folder 50/36)
    - University of Miami, 1967 (Box-folder 50/37)
    - University of Minnesota, 1942 Jan. 16 (Box-folder 50/38)
    - University of Mississippi, 1948, 1969 (Box-folder 50/39)
    - University of North Carolina, 1936-48 (Box-folder 50/40)
    - University of Oklahoma 1966, 1972, 1981 (Box-folder 50/41)
    - University of Oregon, 1966 Feb. 23 (Box-folder 50/42)
    - University of Pennsylvania see: Kohn, Hans
    - University of Redlands, 1966 Sept. 6 (Box-folder 50/43)
    - The University of Rochester, 1926-28, 1941, 1966, n.d. see also: Kaun, Bernhard see also: Luening, Otto and Ethel (Box-folder 50/44)
    - University of Southern California, 1956, 1974 see also: Chasins, Abram (Box-folder 50/45)
    - University of Tennessee, 1948 (Box-folder 50/46)
    - University of Texas, 1937-38, 1966 see also: Kohn, Hans (Box-folder 50/47)
    - University of Washington, 1947 (Box-folder 50/48)
    - University of Washington Press, 1973-74, 1981, 1987 (Box-folder 50/49)
    - University of West Florida, 1971 May 20 (Box-folder 50/50)
    - University of Wisconsin, 1937-41, 1951, n.d. see also: Johansen, Gunnar (Box-folder 50/51)
    - University of Wyoming, 1972-73, 1981, n.d. (Box-folder 50/52)
    - Ussher, Bruno David, 1939, n.d. (Box-folder 51/1)
    - Vanguard Press, Inc., 1964 July 9 (Box-folder 51/2)
    - Vassar College, 1939-41, 1974 (Box-folder 51/3)
    - Veterans Administration, 1948 Mar. 19 (Box-folder 51/4)
    - Viking Press, Inc., 1964 Mar. 31 (Box-folder 51/5)
    - Voice of America, 1968 Mar. 26 (Box-folder 51/6)
    - "V" Miscellaneous (Box-folder 51/7)
    - WNIB/WNIZ, 1988 Apr. 23 (Box-folder 51/8)
    - W.P.A. Federal Music Project, 1934-39 (Box-folder 51/9)
    - W. W. Norton and Company, 1964-65 (Box-folder 51/10)
    - Wagner Memorial Lutheran College, 1941 Nov. 15 (Box-folder 51/11)
    - Washington and Jefferson College, 1967-[68?] (Box-folder 51/12)
    - Washington Post, 1974 (Box-folder 51/13)
    - Washington University, 1948 Mar. 29 (Box-folder 51/14)
    - Waubay United Church of Christ, 1973 Jan. 2 (Box-folder 51/15)
    - Weigl, Karl, 1919, 1938-77 and Vally Weigl (Box-folder 51/16)
    - Wesleyan University, 1947, 1963-64, n.d. see also: Kohn, Hans (Box-folder 51/17)
    - Wessel, Mark, 1939-47, 1964, n.d. (Box-folder 51/18)
    - Western Gerontological Society, 1985 Feb. 28 (Box-folder 51/19)
    - Whedon, Harriet, 1938-51, n.d. (Box-folder 51/20)
    - Who is Who in Music, Inc., Ltd., 1948 July 28 (Box-folder 51/21)
    - Who's Who in American Education, Inc., 1939 (Box-folder 51/22)
    - Wigeland, Norman, 1915-19, n.d. (Box-folder 51/23)
    - Wigglesworth, Frank, 1941-44, n.d. (Box-folder 51/24)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1947, 1954-59, 1967-73 (Box-folder 51/25)
    - World Biographical Encylopedia, 1939, 1940, 1948 (Box-folder 51/26)
    - Wright, Cedric, 1928-1959, undated, Folders: 51/27 1928-49 51/28 1950-59 51/29 Undated (Box-folder 51/27-29)
    - "W" Miscellaneous (Box-folder 51/30)
    - Yale University, 1940-45, 1963-66 (Box-folder 51/31)
    - "Y" Miscellaneous (Box-folder 51/32)
    - Zimmermann, Richard, 1946-48, 1976-88 (Box-folder 51/33)
    - "Z" Miscellaneous (Box-folder 51/34)
- Iconography, 1898-1990 (Box 52-53, Mapcase 3)
  The series is comprised of photographs, artworks by Ernst Bacon and others, and posters of performances of Ernst Bacon.
  Arrangement is by format.
  - Photography (Box 52, 53)
    - Ernst Bacon, Folders: 52/1, 53a/7 Alone 52/2 with Father 52/3 with Mother and her maternal families 52/4, 53a/8 with Siblings 52/5 with Family 52/6 with Wives 52/7, 53a/9 with others (Box-folder 52/1-7, Box-folder 53a/7-9)
    - Other photos (Box-folder 52/8)
  - Artwork (Box 52, 53)
    - Grossglockner und Pasterze von Glocknerhaus, in pencil (Box-folder 52/9)
    - Mont Blanc, pencil drawing (Box-folder 52/9)
    - ...Lisbon, watercolor (Box-folder 52/9)
    - The Barber, reproduction (Box-folder 52/9)
    - Caricature of Ernst Bacon, by Sotomayor in ink and 3 drawings in ink by Ernst Bacon (Box-folder 53a/10)
    - Frescoed ceiling of St. Absurduni, in pencil (Box-folder 53a/11)
  - Posters (Box 53a, Mapcase 3)
    - 1918 Apr. 11 (Box-folder 53a/12)
    - [1919] Dec. 11 (Box-folder 53a/13)
    - [1931] Oct. 1 (Mapcase-drawer 3/1)
    - [1931] Nov. 24 (Mapcase-drawer 3/1)
    - [1937] Feb. 9 (Box-folder 53a/14)
    - 1967 May 11 (Box-folder 53a/15)
- Miscellaneous, 1898-1990 (Box 52-53)
  This series contains programs, a radio interview, financial/legal, Publicity releases, clippings, a Who's who certificate, dance cards, academic material, appointment books, writing by others, and lists.
  - Academic materials, 1907-17, n.d. (Box-folder 52/10)
  - Appointment books, 1931, 1935 (Box-folder 52/11)
  - Who's Who In America, Certificate, 1978-79 (Box-folder 52/12)
  - Clippings, 1920, 1942, 1965-76, n.d. (Box-folder 52/13)
  - Dance Cards, 1915, n.d. (Box-folder 52/14)
  - Financial/legal, 1916-26, 1936-48, 1964-77, n.d. see also: General Correspondence, Circle Blueprint Company, Inc. see also: General Correspondence, Consolidated Edison Company see also: General Correspondence, Office of the Assessor (Box-folder 52/15)
  - Interview with Ernst Bacon, 1982 Apr. 23 (Box-folder 52/16)
  - Lists, 1911, 1929, 1947-48, 1986-87, n.d. and undated (Box-folder 52/17-18)
  - Programs, 1898, 1915-26, 1937-44, 1952-53, 1975, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 52/19)
  - Publicity releases, 1901, 1915-16, 1940, 1951-55, n.d. (Box-folder 52/20)
  - Writings by others (Box-folder 53a/6)